[upbeat tropical music]
[欢快的热带音乐]
♪ ♪
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[laughs]
[笑]
Wah!
哇！
- [relaxed moan]
Oh, Sheldon.
- [放松的呻吟声]
哦，谢尔顿。
You're so romantic.
你真浪漫。
- It's all
about you today, Karen.
- 就这样了
今天关于你，凯伦。
- Oh, this makes up
- 哦，这弥补了
for a lot of your
stupidity lately, Plankton.
对于你的很多
最近很愚蠢，浮游生物。
- Plankton's stepped away
for a moment.
- 浮游生物走开了
一会儿。
The name's Ray Ray,
我的名字叫雷雷，
and I am at your service,
m'lady.
我随时为您服务，
女士。
Pow!
噗！
- Oh, kiss me, pipsqueak.
- 哦，吻我吧，小皮。
I mean, Ray Ray.
我是说，雷雷。
- Grandma!
- 奶奶！
I told you never to call me
on this screen.
我告诉过你永远不要给我打电话
在此屏幕上。
- Sheldon, is that you?
- 谢尔顿，是你吗？
- Yes, it's me, Grandma.
- 是的，是我，奶奶。
Always nice to hear from you.
Okay, gotta go.
很高兴收到你的来信。
好吧，该走了。
- Okay, sweetie.
- 好吧，亲爱的。
See you tomorrow at eight AM sharp.
明天早上八点整见。
- Right, see you then.
What a minute, what?
- 好吧，到时候见。
等了一分钟，什么？
Eight AM?
上午八点？
Um, what's happening
at eight AM, Grandma?
嗯，发生了什么事
早上八点，奶奶？
- Don't you remember, silly?
- 你不记得了吗，傻瓜？
You promised me you'd own
the Krusty Krab
你答应过我你会拥有
蟹堡王
by my 90th birthday.
到我 90 岁生日时。
Well, my 90th is tomorrow!
好吧，明天就是我的 90 岁生日了！
You do own the Krusty Krab now, right?
你现在确实拥有蟹堡王了，对吧？
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[explosion]
[爆炸]
Lie, that's it!
谎言，就是这样！
Uh, you're darn right I own
the Krusty Krab, Grandma,
呃，你说得对，我拥有
蟹堡王，奶奶，
and I can't wait to give you
我迫不及待地想给你
the grand tour
tomorrow morning.
盛大的旅行
明天早上。
- Aww, see you then.
- 哇哦，到时候见。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- That smack was for Plankton.
- 那是给浮游生物的。
Now bring back Ray Ray.
现在把雷雷带回来。
- Oh, what am I
gonna do, Karen?
- 哦，我是什么
会做什么，凯伦？
How am I gonna fool
Grandma tomorrow?
我要怎样愚弄
明天奶奶吗？
- Oh, okay, I guess
bath time is over.
-哦，好吧，我想
洗澡时间结束了。
Why don't you and Ray Ray
take a long walk
你为什么不和雷雷
散步
off a short plank?
短木板？
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
Gotta think, gotta think.
必须想一想，必须想一想。
Come on, brain!
来吧，大脑！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- This way to the Krusty Krab!
- 这边去蟹堡！
Pull right in and order
a Krabby Patty!
向右拉并订购
蟹肉饼！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Whoo! Whoop, whoop.
呼！呼呼，呼呼。
Ooh.
Aah.
哦。
啊。
[birds cawing]
[鸟鸣声]
[exciting grunting]
[令人兴奋的咕噜声]
Whew.
呼。
Ow!
噢！
- SpongeBoob,
ya gotta help me.
- 海绵布布，
你必须帮助我。
- Sorry, Plankton,
what can I do to help you?
- 对不起，浮游生物，
我能为您做些什么吗？
- [straining]
- [紧张]
This is not an evil scheme.
这不是一个邪恶的计划。
The truth is I promised
my grandma
事实是我答应过的
我的奶奶
I would own the Krusty Krab
by her 90th birthday.
我想拥有蟹堡王
到她 90 岁生日时。
So I need Krabs
to play pretend tomorrow
所以我需要螃蟹
明天假装玩
and fool my grandma
into believing
并愚弄我的奶奶
相信
I'm the new owner,
otherwise she will think
我是新主人
不然她会想
I'm a big loser.
Got it?
我是个大失败者。
知道了？
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Well, I believe you, Plankton,
好吧，我相信你，浮游生物，
but I'm not sure Mr. Krabs
is gonna buy it.
但我不确定蟹老板
会买它。
- I'm not gonna buy what?
- 我不打算买什么？
I ain't buying it!
This whole grandma thing
我不买！
这整个奶奶的事
sounds just like
another phony plot
听起来就像
另一个虚假的情节
to steal me formula.
偷我的配方。
- I was hoping I wouldn't have
to resort to this, Eugene,
- 我本来希望我不会
诉诸于此，尤金，
but...
[straining]
但是...
[紧张]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- [gasps] SpongeBob, there's
something wrong with his eye.
- [喘气]海绵宝宝，有
他的眼睛出了问题。
- That's Plankton's rarely
seen sincere face, Mr. Krabs,
- 浮游生物很少见
看到蟹老板真诚的脸，
and it means for once
he is telling the truth.
这意味着一次
他说的是实话。
- You know, I have
a grandma too.
- 你知道，我有
还有一位奶奶。
- Aww.
- [sobs]
- 哇。
- [抽泣]
All right, I buy it.
- [gasps]
好吧，我买了。
- [喘气]
- Thank you.
- 谢谢。
- First things first.
- 首先，要事第一。
That should keep it safe
for six to eight hours.
这应该保证它的安全
六到八小时。
All right, me pretties,
好吧，我漂亮，
let's make this place
pro-Plankton pronto.
让我们把这个地方
亲浮游生物很快。
- Ahhh!
- 啊啊！
- [straining]
- [紧张]
all: Mmm, mmm.
全体：嗯嗯。
- Now everyone remember,
for the rest of the day
- 现在大家都记住了，
当天剩下的时间
Plankton is the--
[stammers]
浮游生物是——
[结巴]
Plankton's boss.
浮游生物的老大。
- Hi, Grandma.
- 嗨，奶奶。
Happy birthday.
生日快乐。
- Nice to see you again,
Grandma Plankton.
- 很高兴再次见到你，
浮游生物奶奶。
- Ugh.
Who invited C-Pee-Eww?
- 呃。
谁邀请了 C-Pee-Eww？
[laughs]
[笑]
- All right, I tried.
- 好吧，我试过了。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Let me help you with
your bag, Grandma.
让我帮你
你的包，奶奶。
Ouch!
哎哟!
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Well, here we are,
Grandma.
- 好吧，我们到了，
奶奶。
Welcome to the Krusty Plankton.
欢迎来到库斯蒂浮游生物。
I named it after you.
我以你的名字命名它。
- Oh, well, aren't you
a sweet grandson?
-哦，好吧，你不是吗
一个可爱的孙子？
Who are they?
他们是谁？
- They're just
my employees, Grandma.
- 他们只是
我的员工，奶奶。
Meet SpongeBob and Eugene.
来认识一下海绵宝宝和尤金。
both: Hello, Grandma Plankton.
两人：你好，浮游生物奶奶。
- They look like
very nice boys,
- 他们看起来像
非常好的男孩，
and I'll be they're even
nicer when they're working.
我会和他们打平
他们工作的时候更好。
- You heard, Grandma!
- 你听到了，奶奶！
We ain't running
a welcome wagon here!
我们没有奔跑
这里有迎宾车！
Get back to work!
回去工作吧！
- [stammering]
- [结巴]
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
Yeah, sure thing, Plankton.
是的，当然，浮游生物。
- That's Mr. Plankton
to you, busboy.
- 那是浮游生物先生
给你，服务员。
- Sorry, Mr. Plankton.
- 对不起，浮游生物先生。
It won't happen again.
这样的事不会再发生了。
[straining]
[紧张]
- Oh, look, that one's
napping on the job.
- 哦，看，那个是
在工作中打瞌睡。
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- Nap time's over, loafer!
- 午睡时间结束了，懒汉！
- Okay, who's the wise guy?
- 好吧，谁是聪明人？
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Ohh.
- 哦。
Oh, my goodness.
哦，我的天啊。
Who is this
handsome young man?
这是谁
英俊的年轻人？
- Oh, that's Squidward.
He's nobody.
- 哦，那是章鱼哥。
他什么都不是。
Moving along...
继续前进...
- Mm. Squidward.
- 毫米。章鱼哥。
Didn't we meet
at an early bird dinner?
我们没见过面吗
早鸟晚餐？
- Ooh, I think someone
has a not-so-secret admirer.
- 哦，我想有人
有一个不那么秘密的仰慕者。
[laughs]
[笑]
Ow!
噢！
- All right, lady,
I don't normally say this,
- 好吧，女士，
我一般不说这个
but got off my nose.
但从我的鼻子里消失了。
- Go along with it, Squidward.
- 随它去吧，章鱼哥。
- Or you're fired.
- 或者你被解雇了。
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
So, Grandma Plankton,
所以，浮游生物奶奶，
where have you been
all my life?
你去哪儿了
我一生？
- [chuckles]
Call me Lily.
- [轻笑]
叫我莉莉吧。
- Okay, Grandma,
you're embarrassing me now.
- 好的，奶奶，
你现在让我很尴尬。
- To the kitchen, Squidward.
- 去厨房，章鱼哥。
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
- Try one of our
Planky Patties, Grandma.
- 尝试我们的一款
板条肉饼，奶奶。
Fresh off the grill.
刚从烤架上下来。
[cheerful music]
[欢快的音乐]
[orchestral fanfare]
[管弦乐曲]
- I'll need
my teeth for this.
- 我需要
我的牙齿为此。
Whoops.
哎呀。
Oops.
I dropped my choppers.
我放下了我的直升机。
Oh, well.
那好吧。
I guess Squidward will have
to chew it for me.
我猜章鱼哥会有
给我咀嚼它。
- Oh, sure, I'll--what?
- 哦，当然，我会-什么？
Aah.
啊。
- [chuckles] That's it,
chew it up real good.
- [笑] 就是这样，
嚼起来真的很好。
That's enough.
My turn.
这就够了。
轮到我了。
- Aah.
- 啊啊。
[chuckles]
[笑声]
Delicious.
可口的。
[all groan]
[全都呻吟]
- Oh, Sheldon,
you've outdone yourself.
- 哦，谢尔顿，
你已经超越了自己。
You really are a master chef.
你真是一位大厨。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Thank you, Sheldon.
- 谢谢你，谢尔顿。
You've really
made my birthday
你真的已经
给我过生日
something extra special
this year.
一些特别的东西
今年。
- All right, Grandma.
Got your bag?
- 好吧，奶奶。
你的包拿到了吗？
You are out the door,
and that is that.
你在门外，
就是这样。
- Oh, just one more thing.
- 哦，还有一件事。
[all groan]
[全都呻吟]
My last birthday wish
我最后一个生日愿望
is to get a photo of me
是为了给我拍张照片
posing with the Krabby Patty
secret formula.
与蟹肉饼合影
秘密配方。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
Krabs?
螃蟹？
- Fine. Anything to get that
bag with a bag out of here.
- 美好的。任何事情都能得到
拎着袋子离开这里。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
all: Say cheese.
全体：说奶酪。
both: Cheese.
两者：奶酪。
- Ahhh!
- 啊啊！
[all scream]
[所有人尖叫]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Finally, the secret formula
is mine!
最后是秘方
是我的！
- I knew your sincerity
was insincere, sir!
- 我知道你的诚意
先生不真诚！
- I didn't know anything
about this, Eugene, honest.
- 我什么都不知道
关于这一点，尤金，老实说。
But I love it!
但我喜欢它！
Now we can rule the world
as a family, eh, Grandma?
现在我们可以统治世界
作为一个家庭，呃，奶奶？
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
- Sorry, Sheldon, but I'm not
sharing this formula with you.
- 抱歉，谢尔顿，但我不是
与大家分享这个公式。
- But Grandma!
- 但是奶奶！
- Adios, mi amor!
- 再见，我的爱人！
Mmmm.
嗯。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- [laughs maniacally]
- [疯狂地笑]
- Why? Why did I lie?
- 为什么？我为什么撒谎？
- Why?
Why did I pretend?
- 为什么？
我为什么要假装？
- Why? Why did I
give her my formula?
- 为什么？为什么我
给她我的配方吗？
- Why? Why wouldn't we
be open on Tuesday, idiot.
- 为什么？我们为什么不呢
周二开门，白痴。
all: What have we done?
所有人：我们做了什么？
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
I have the secret formula.
我有秘密配方。
[laughs]
This world is mine!
[笑]
这个世界是我的！
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
all chanting:
Grandma! Grandma! Grandma!
所有人都在喊口号：
奶奶！奶奶！奶奶！
- Darling, why don't you
toss the peasants
- 亲爱的，你为什么不呢？
扔农民
a little something?
一点东西？
[laughs]
[笑]
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
[snores]
[打鼾]
- I'll take that,
thank you very much.
- 我会接受的，
非常感谢。
Safe and sound.
安全无恙。
- Happy birthday, Grandma.
- 生日快乐，奶奶。
[groans]
[呻吟]